Hi, and welcome to Mia-Platform Video
Pills.
In this video, we will see how we have
improved the experience of connecting
and editing a cluster within
Mia-Platform Console.
From the homepage, you can click on the icons
besides your platforms,
or you can open the right menu
and click on your companies
to view all your platforms.
By clicking on one of the displayed
platforms,
you can access the cluster section
to view all your connected clusters.
In this example, the platform doesn't
have any connected cluster.
We can create a new cluster connection
by clicking on the Add cluster connection
button.
As you can see, we support by default
all the major cloud providers
like GCP, a AWS, Azure and Oracle Cloud.
You can also connect
additional ones as long as they have
a Kubernetes or OpenShift distribution.
Let's create
a new cluster connection on GCP.
Let's select Kubernetes as a Runtime Service.
At this point,
we should insert the cluster details.
So we add the cluster ID,
the geographic location
and a description.
Finally,
we have to complete the connection
by adding the cluster URL,
the Proxy URL,
a cluster token,
and optionally an authority certificate.
This message confirms
that that the cluster
is finally connected.
As Mia-Platform supports
multi-cloud environments,
you can add another cluster
from a different provider.
Let's click again
on Add Cluster Connection.
Select “other” as cloud provider
and Kubernetes is runtime service.
We now fill in the new cluster details.
Finally,
we insert the cluster and proxy URL,
The cluster token, and eventually
the certificate of authority.
The new cluster is connected.
Within your environment.
You will find the two connected clusters
with the details about the runtime
services, the Kubernetes versions,
and the cluster URL.