Hi, and welcome to Mia-Platform
Video Pills.
Today we will see
a new way of managing providers in
Mia-Platform Console at the platform level.
Providers can be generically defined
as a means of storing information
about external services.
Starting on the page that contains all
your projects, click on Platform Overview.
The Providers tab is located on the left
sidebar.
On this page, you have the list of providers.
You can see that we already created
Mia-Platform, GitLab and Azure DevOps.
Each provider is listed with the type
of capacity and service used.
Let's try to add a new one.
Click on Add Provider Connection.
A modal window is displayed.
You can choose from a range of providers.
Click on Get Lab.
On the next page we can select
the features used by the provider,
the secret manager, the get provider,
the CI/CD tool for all of them.
Next, you enter the name of the provider,
the basic API URL and a brief description
if necessary.
Following the wizard,
we can now enter the credentials.
On the last page,
in the Advanced section,
we can enter a Certificate Authority
and the proxy if required.
Let's add
the provider and close the modal.
We now find our new GitLab
provider in the list.
If you need to change it, just
click on the arrow and
edit the field you want to modify.
With this feature,
you can manage providers from one place,
defining their capabilities, entering
credentials, certifications, authority
and proxies.