Hi everyone and welcome to the Mia-Platform
tutorials. Today we're going to take a look
at the Mia-Assistant, which is the AI chatbot
in the Mia-Platform Console. Imagine that
you are a new developer on the Mia-Platform
Console and you want to orchestrate a saga,
but you don't know what to do. This is where the
Mia-Assistant comes in handy! It facilitates the
understanding of the console features and
exploration of the product; it also speeds
up your search in docs and suggests things that
can be done on the Mia-Platform console. It also
simplifies your access to Features. So let's
begin: go ahead here on the lefthand side and
click on Mia-Assistant. This is going to open
the chatbot that will help answer all of your
questions. Let's give it a few commands to test
it out. Let's start with: "Can I orchestrate a
saga?". As you can see here it will return all of
the options for you to orchestrate a saga and will
also link different documents that you can use
to learn more about this. For the second command,
let's go ahead and give: "Can you make
an example of an orchestrated saga?".
As you can see here the Mia-Assistant
is going to give you an actual real life
example that you can use to create
an orchestrated Saga. Perfect. Now,
if you want to further understand this you
can also ask:"What if it was a saga of a
loyalty program?". As you can see here it
will give you an in-depth answer about the
Saga of a loyalty program. You can also ask:
"How can I install the Flow Manager using the
Console?". Here it will give you the exact code
that you need to install the Flow Manager using
the Console. Perfect, let's go ahead and thank
the Mia-Assistant for helping us with this task,
and thank you guys for watching.
As always if you have any questions
feel free to reach out to us via email, on
our website or book a demo with us! Thank you.