Hi, and welcome to Mia-Platform Video
Pills.
In this video, we'll see the new No Code
configuration of Mia-Platform Fast Data.
Let's start by opening the design area
and then click
on the projection section.
Here you will find the connected systems
of record.
In this case,
we have a delivery system already linked
by clicking on the new ER Schema tab.
You can view all the ER Schemas created,
ready to be edited or deleted.
Now let's create a new ER Schema.
This is the new No Code
interface of Mia-Platform Fast Data.
On the right side
you find all the systems of record
together with their projections.
While on the left side,
there's the configuration interface
with the JSON schema.
You can easily drag and drop a projection
inside the configurator
to automatically create the JSON file.
To create the ER Schema,
we just need to insert all the projections
and connect them among each other.
Now, by clicking on each projection,
you can see all their detailed data
while by clicking on the arrows
you can select the connection type
and set up the connection rules.
In this case,
we set up a one to many connection between
the customer and the order projections.
Then we click on the “Edit Rules” button
to define the relationship
between these two objects
so that the customer ID is equal to
the customer ID in the order.
In the same way,
we set up a one to many connection type
between the orders and the products,
as an order
may contain more than one product,
and a product can be part of one order.
As before,
we need to define the connection rules
between these two objects
so that the order ID is equal to the order
idea of the products.
You can also set up unique relationships
between the objects.
For example,
you can select that a single product field
is equal to specific order
fields or value.
In addition,
you can also add a group to combine
a set of rules with a logical operation.
The air schema is finally defined.
By opening the left tab,
we can see that the JSON schema has been
auto generated and it is fully compatible
with the previous versions of
Mia-Platform Fast Data.
Moreover, by clicking on the top arrows,
you can move back
and forth in the changes.
Now we can move on to
the the single View section.
Click to edit the Single View settings.
Open the Single View Creators
tab to view all the microservices
managing the single views.
Let's change the default ER Schema,
so that it becomes the new one
we created before.
As you can see,
it has been filled in
with the previous configuration.
By clicking on the ER Schema link,
we can go back to the no code interface.