Hi everyone and welcome to the Mia-Platform
tutorials. Today we're going to take a look at
Custom frontend as an IFrame. What is an IFrame?
An IFrame is a simple way to embed a web page or
a web component in another web page or another web
component. The most common use of an IFrame is to
load content from another page into another site
within the page. The child site can load its own
content and cookies so sites may allow it where
they don't allow direct hot linking content. Using
an IFrame is the accepted way to embed a YouTube
video or a Google Maps content into your web
page. We brought this concept to our Mia-Platform
Console. Since our Console is a tool born to embed
other Cloud Native tools, we have an interface
where you can configure more advanced features
and our users can directly access a different
interface within the console. For this example,
let's imagine that you are someone who uses
Backstage and the Mia-Platform Console on a
regular working day. In this video we will enter
the Core Enterprise Platform section in our
companies and we will go to the Backstage icon. As
you can see, here you have the Mia-Platform demo
Backstage app within the Mia-Platform Console
itself. Here you can enter as a guest user and
carry out with your proceedings. As you can see
this is a super easy way for you to integrate
another web page into the Mia-Platform Console.
We hope this was helpful and as always if you have
any questions feel free to reach out to us or book
a demo on the Mia-Platform website. Thank you!