Hi and welcome to Mia-Platform video
Pills.
In this video,
we will show you the new low code
capability of Mia-Platform Back Office.
Let's start.
We have already installed the Back Office
application.
In fact,
the sidebar shows the dedicated tab.
Click on it
and take a moment to explore the section.
We reached the pages
section where we can create a new page
for our Back Office.
By default, an example page is created.
Next, we have the layout section
where we can edit
the basic properties
and configurations of the theme.
We move on to the settings section,
where we find the URIs
error pages, Mount Point, import
map and shared properties.
Next,
you can see the configuration section
of the web server with headers,
entry points and content types.
At the end, It is the advanced configuration,
which allows us to edit the code directly
with the help of a preview.
To see how easy it is to manage
the Back Office, let us create a new page.
Back to the pages. Click on Add new page.
Once the modal is displayed, select
iFrame as the page type,
decide a name and a rendering route.
Click on next,
Enter the iFrame source and click Save.
The new page is now listed in the table
To display the new page
in the navigation bar.
Go to the layout tab.
Here, a new menu item can be added.
Go to menu
items and click edit properties.
Add a new item
and write the configuration.
Save.
We now have a new menu item.
Go to the advanced
tab to see a running preview
Save the project.
Now, deploy it.
If we navigate
to the public URL,
we can see the new page in the sidebar.
Let's create a new page type.
Instead of iFrame,
select Compose.
Call the page “Users”.
Use “Users” also for the rendering route.
Click on next.
Here we can see that we can choose
different page templates such as:
blank page, page with table, calendar view, picture
gallery and details page.
Each page has its own goal.
For example, a calendar page might be
useful for an appointment manager.
An image gallery page might be perfect
if you have to manage various media files.
Go ahead and choose the page
with the table template.
Save it.
Unlike the iFrame page type,
the compose page type
allows you to configure several options.
Click on the button.
A preview page is opening.
Here you can adapt the page your business
needs, starting with the page name
or the text of the search bar up
to some advanced functions.
For example, the table field.
We now connect the data collections.
In this case under connectors
and adapters.
We select “/users” for the CRUD service.
Once done, add the new item to the menu.
Instead of using the low code
configuration, you now use
the advanced settings
where you can directly add the code.
Here's the new menu item.
Save the configuration.
Now we can deploy and see the result.
Refreshing the page.
We find our page with the tables already
populated with user data.
Finally, we customize our layout.
For example, we can switch the navigation layout.
Let us say that our brand is green.
Of course, we can modify our layout
with a green user interface.
Thanks to this low code function,
the Back Office becomes a powerful tool,
highly customizable and quickly adaptable
to your business needs.
In a short time, a data-rich, scalable
and high performance
tool can be implemented
abstracting the complexity of maintenance.