Hi, and welcome to Mia-Platform Video
Pills.
In this video, we will show
you Mia-Platform Bucket Storage.
Bucket Storage extends the functionality
of Mia-Platform Fast Data
and provides storage of raw data.
This data is ready to be re-injected
when needed or can be served to business
intelligence, relieving DB administration.
To better understand how it works,
we will only show you the microservices
to be installed in a use case.
As you can see, we have already set up
the Mia-Platform Fast Data projections
with a ER Schema with these entries:
customer, order, and product.
In addition,
we already have a Single View called
Order History.
Let's install the first microservice.
Go to the microservices section and search
for the Ingestion Storage Service.
During installation,
remember to set the correct environment
variables, configuration
maps and Secret Keys.
Let’s deploy it
We can now see that
we have our empty bucket.
With Postman,
we populate our bucket with the customer.
Now we can see that
we have generated a new customer.
We now install the second microservice we need:
Ingestion Reloader.
Find it on Mia-Platform marketplace and install it
with all the configurations and secrets
as we did before.
Expose the API and deploy it.
Now we can take a look at our use case.
In MongoDB,
we already have some pre-filled data,
topics already mentioned
at the beginning of this video.
As you can see, we have a customer,
some orders, a single view that aggregates
the orders, a number of products
and returning to the single view,
within the orders we can see the products.
Let us switch to our bucket
and see that we have folders
for each topic.
For example, we can see the orders here.
Now we delete our orders and show how
to reinject the same data from the bucket.
The order collection is now empty.
We also have no data in the Single View.
To reingest the data, we go to Postman.
We declare that we want to input order
data.
Let's click on Send.
Now, going back to MongoDB,
you can see again orders both in the topic
and in the single view.
The main benefits of Bucket Storage
include: providing large storage space
at a reduced cost,
becoming an easily accessible repository
for backup and compliance
reasons, enabling easy exposure of data
to business intelligence tools.
Try it with
Mia-Platform v11.