Hi, and welcome to Mia-Platform Pills.
Today we will show you how to create
service accounts,
which are not human users
that can be employed
to implement automated processes
with machine-to-machine communication.
Let's start.
Access to the Platform Overview
by clicking on the icon.
Once on the page, simply
click on “Identities” in the left sidebar.
Here you have an overview
of all the users on the platform.
Now let us try to add a new Service Account
which we have just said
is a non-human user.
Click on “Add User”
and then on “Add Service Account”.
Firstly, give it a name.
There are then two different methods
of adding it
using Client Secret Basic
or a Private Key JWT.
Choose the Client Secret Basic method.
Now, as an actual user,
you need to assign a role
representing a set of permissions
within the platform.
Once created,
the credential must be saved.
For security reasons,
the generated Client Secret
is only visible once in this screen.
If you don't save it,
you will not able to retrieve it.
So click on the copy icon
and store it in a safe place.
The client idea is displayed
in the table instead.
Let us now add a new Service Account
with the Private Key JWT method.
Click on the “Add User” button and perform
the previous steps.
Here you can paste your public certificate
while your private certificate
will be used to sign the token.
Assign the role and remember
to save the key ID.
Let's test our Service Account.
To the purpose of this video,
we will generate a token
only for the client secret basic method.
The token is created by taking the clientID:clientsecret
encoding it in base64,
creating an intermediate token.
The call will return this token.
As you may notice, this token has
an expiry date. For long term operations,
it is necessary to request it
several times.
Remember that it is always possible
to change the role of a Service Account
or delete it.
Service Accounts
can be created on a platform, project,
or runtime environment level, based on where
they need to perform their task.
For example, here
we're creating it in a project
so it will be applied
only in the current space.
Service Accounts can automate processes
acting as real users.
For example, they can trigger automatic
deploys or to perform monitoring actions.