Hi everyone, this is Rhea from Mia-Platform and
today I'm going to show you how you can create
a CRUD service using the Mia-Platform Console.
Let's go ahead and start with the Mia-Platform
Console. We're in the design section. Let's go
ahead and scroll down to MongoDB CRUDs and here
we can click on "Create a new CRUD". Let's
start by giving it a name: for this example,
I'm going to give it the name "employee2"
and click on "Create". Perfect, as you can
see here this is a collection of employee2 and
all of the fields are attached below. Let's add
some of our own fields. Let's go ahead and write
"Name" set the field type as string and click on
"Create". Let's add another one for "Last name"
or surname, create, set the type as string and
go ahead and create, and then we can add the
third one as "email ID" where we also set the
type as string and go ahead and click on create.
Perfect, as you can see collection employee2 now
has three different fields that we have added:
name, surname and email ID, which are all type
string. Once you're happy with that we need to go
ahead and create and expose the endpoint. Let's
scroll in this menu to find "Endpoint" and create
a new endpoint. Let's name the base part of this
endpoint "employee 2 ", let's select the endpoint
type as CRUD and then choose the base part. The
base part is employee2, the crud we just created.
Let's go ahead and click on "Create". Once this is
created of course you can see here you can change
the security and documentation settings and once
this is created it's time for us to save our
configuration. Let's move ahead to the left hand
side menu and click on "Save configuration". When
you're saving your configuration you will have to
write a title commit - for this example let's go
ahead and write "commit employee2" and go ahead
and save that. Perfect, your configuration is now
saved and everything is up to date. The next step
would be moving into the deploy section. Let's go
ahead here into the deploy section and select our
branch. Our branch is master and here we can go
ahead and smart deploy our CRUD function. Perfect,
as you can see our CRUD function is ready and
we can go ahead and click on Smart Deploy.
Perfect, as you can see your deploy is now
successful and now we can move into the
runtime section. Perfect, now we've entered
our runtime section where you can see all of
the pods that are running and you can see that
all of them are at status "okay" - this means
we can go ahead into the overview section and
enter environments where in which we'll be able
to see the runtime environments and access the
API portal. We're in the development section,
let's go ahead to documentation
which opens up your API portal.
Perfect, we've now entered our API portal
where we can see our function employee2,
the CRUD service we created. Let's go ahead and
put in some data using the "Post" function. As you
can see here we can add some parameters, so "name"
let's go ahead and put in Rhea, "surname" let's go
ahead and put in Arora and "email ID" let's go
ahead and put in rheaaroraxyz@gmail.com.Perfect,
once you're happy with this we can go ahead and
click on "Try it". Once you try it this is going
to generate an ID. Let's go ahead and copy paste
that ID and now let's move into the get function.
This is where we'll be able to return a list of
all of the documents we've added in employee2,
so let's go ahead into get the get function
and put in an ID and go ahead and click on
"Try it". Perfect, as you can see this has
worked well: you're able to see the name,
the surname and the email ID. So that's
basically how you create a CRUD service
on the Mia-Platform console - it's super easy
easy! Let us know if you have any questions,
feel free to reach out to us via email or
book a demo call anytime you like. Thank you!