Hi everyone and welcome to the Mia-Platform
tutorials. Today we're going to see a new
way of managing providers in the Mia-Platform
Console at the platform level. Providers can
be generically defined as a means of storing
information about external services.To begin
with we're on the main Mia-Platform homepage,
let's go ahead and enter one of the projects.
As you can see here in the left hand side menu
there is a tab and under Administration you can
find the provider section. You can see some
of the providers we've already created such
as Mia-Platform GitLab and Azure DevOps. Each
provider is listed with the type of capacity
and service that is used. Let's go ahead and
try to add a new provider connection. Here
you can see a modal window is displayed with all
of the providers existing: there's Azure DevOps,
BitBucket, GitHub, GitLab and more. For this
example let's go ahead and click on GitLab. As
you can see here all of the capabilities that you
want to use this provider for have been selected,
but you can go ahead and select whichever ones
you like from Secret Manager, CI/CD Tool and
GitProvider. Once you're happy with that go ahead
and click on next: here you can add your provider
name, then you need to add the API base URL, and then you need to add just the base URL.
You can also enter a short description if
you'd like. Once you're happy with filling in
the provider details, you can go ahead to the
credentials section. In the credential section
you need to add an access token. Once that is
added we will move on to the Advance section.
In the advance section you can add a Certificate
Authority and also a proxy if you'd like. Once
you're happy with this let's go ahead and add
provider. Now you can see a provider connection
has been created. You can go ahead and close the
model and go to your provider itself. As you can
see in this list you will be able to see the new
provider that we just created; if you would like
to make any edits to this you can just click on
the arrow and go ahead and edit the credentials,
the advanced credentials or even remove the
connection if you like. With this we have seen
how we can create a provider connection and manage
it in the Mia-Platform Console. With this feature
you can manage providers from one place, defining
their capabilities, entering their credentials,
certificate authorities and proxies. Thank
you for watching and as always if you have
any questions feel free to reach out to us
or book a demo on the Mia-Platform website!