Hi everyone, this is Rhea from Mia-Platform
and today I'm going to show you how you can
create a node.js microservice in the Mia-Platform
Console. To begin with, we're in the Mia-Platform
Console, in the design section - let's go ahead and
click on "Create a microservice" from Marketplace.
The Mia-Platform Marketplace is a repository of
microservices that are easily available for your
use. For this example, let's just go ahead and look
up node.js. We're going going to be using the
"Node.js HelloWorld Microservice Example" here. Let's start
by giving it a name: for this example I'm going to
give it the name "books.3". Here, you can see, you
can change the description and also the docker
image name. Let's go ahead and click on "Create" and
continue. Within a couple of moments, your
microservice is going to be created, Perfect, as you
can see the microservice is created. Now let's go
ahead and expose the endpoint. Let's move into the
endpoint section over here, where we will create a
new endpoint. Let's give it a base path name: again,
let's go with "books.3" and then we can select
the type. The type of course is microservice
and here you can select the exact microservice,
the one we just created which is example books.3.
Once you're happy with this, go ahead and click on
"create". As you can see, here you can also change the
security settings and documentation settings of
the endpoint. Once your endpoint has been created
and exposed, it's time to save your local changes.
So let's go over here to the left hand side menu
and click on "Save configuration". While saving the
configuration, you have to write a title commit: for
this example, let's go ahead and write "commit books.3".
Perfect, once you're happy with that go ahead
and save that. Now your configuration is being
saved and loaded. Perfect, everything is up to date
now and we just need to move to the deploy section.
Let's go ahead here to deploy. Perfect, as you can
see here we've entered the branch master and you can
see that our latest microservice which is "books.3" has been built successfully. Once you happy with
this, let's go ahead and click on "Smart deploy". This
just takes a couple of moments to deploy Master on
development. Perfect, our deploy has been successful! Let's move on to the next step which is to run
this. Let's move into the Runtime section, where you
can see each of the pods have a status. Currently
the status is okay for only three of them, but we
need it to be okay for all of them, so let's just
give it a couple of seconds before we can go ahead
and auto refresh this. Perfect, as you can see all
of the pods are ready now and now we just need
to move into the overview section on the left
hand side. Let's move into the overview section
and go into environments, and here we will enter
the runtime environments for the development.
Perfect, let's go ahead to documentation - this
is going to open the API portal for us. Perfect, as
you can see this has opened the API portal where
we have our "get" function for our microservice
books.3. Let's click on the "get" function and
over here you can try it. Let's click on "Try
it". Perfect, as you can see our microservices
hasn't been installed, our endpoint has been
exposed and here is the output "hello world". If you
have any questions feel free to reach out to us
for a demo or send us an email - and thank you for
watching!