Hi and welcome to Mia-Platform Video Pills
Today I will show how we have enriched
the runtime area,
providing it with an extended sidebar
with new tabs for monitoring workloads.
Let's begin.
Once on the project homepage
access the runtime area.
Whereas before in the runtime area
I could only find
the monitoring part of the pods,
now you have the whole workflow
of my infrastructure.
In addition to pods, it is now possible to find: deployments, services, cronjobs, jobs and namespaces.
Let us look at the layout.
On the right side,
you can manually refresh the data
or decide
how often the page should be refreshed.
Then there is the search box
where you can filter the data.
These fields will also be present
in the next tabs,
allowing for a smooth navigation
experience in each section.
As can be seen by clicking on each tab,
the tables provide the relevant
information.
Continue
navigating and click on the namespace.
Here you will find all the details
of the namespace and can copy
Expand the entire code or export
the JSON file.
Monitoring is essential
to deliver better software, therefore, by
enriching the runtime area,
we want to simplify and improve
the way developers
monitor their pods and services.