Hello and welcome to the Mia-Platform Video Pills.
In this video, we will see how to enable
preview of new features
on the Mia-Platform Console.
This will give you the opportunity
to test the functionality of new products,
understand how they fit
into your software's lifecycle,
and immediately
give feedback to improve it.
Starting from the design area,
we notice our default sidebar.
To activate the feature preview function,
go to the top-right navigation bar
and click on your profile icon,
a dropdown menu is displayed.
By clicking on feature preview.
a pop up is displayed.
Inside is a list of all the features
you can preview and activate.
In this video,
you will only see one: the “Dynamic Sidebar”.
Each feature will have a short description
of the benefits and functionality
it is intended to enable.
In addition, you will have the opportunity
to give your feedback
by clicking the button that will open
Mia-Platform Github Discussions.
Clicking on the toggle
you enable the feature.
If you refresh the page,
you can see the new "More Feature" tab.
In this case, the default sidebar
is switched to a different display mode.
Remember that enabled functions
are only active for the user,
triggering them
not for the whole platform.
To disable the new function.
Simply deactivate it.